woodpecker.co 2019-05-30

# Privacy Policy - Woodpecker.co - Learn how we collect and use your personal information.

Effective: January 1, 2015 Last Updated: September 1, 2018

We take your privacy seriously at Woodpecker.co (henceforth referred to as “Woodpecker”,”we,” “us,” “our”), we take great care about how our users’ personal information is used and shared.

This Privacy Policy describes how Woodpecker.co collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Website woodpecker.co (“Website”), Blog blog.woodpecker.co (“Blog”) as well as in the service we provide at app.woodpecker.co (“Service”). Terms “Subscriber,” “You,” “Your” or a related capitalized terms herein shall refer to users of Woodpecker.co regardless of type of subscription (paid premium or free trial).

This Privacy Policy constitutes an addendum to the [Terms of Service](https://woodpecker.co/terms-of-service/). Before you use Woodpecker, please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By using or accessing our Website and/or Service, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy and you agree that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.

## 1\. Information collected by Woodpecker.co

**a.** Woodpecker may collect two types of information: personal (name, email address, company information) or non-personal visitor information (such as: the Device’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, the web page visited before or after you came to our website, information you search for on our website and interactions with the Service).  
**  
b.** If you wish to remain anonymous, use Incognito mode in your browser to ensure that we’re unable to collect any data.

**c.** You may be asked to enter your email address on the Website in order to download a material, or to ask a question about the Service using a live chat installed on the Website. If you wish us not to collect your personal data, you should not provide us with your contact credentials.

**d.** You may be asked to enter your email address on the Blog in order to download material and subscribe to a blog newsletter sent weekly, or an email course list. If you wish us not to collect your personal data, you should not provide us with your contact credentials. Each correspondence concerning blog posts, tutorials, product updates which you receive from us contains unsubscribe link which allows you to withdraw your consent. We reserve our right not to include unsubscribe link in a communication which is necessary to provide you Woodpecker application, such as, but not limited to, maintenance break information or data safety breach notifications, customer success and support information.

**e.** When starting a trial of our Service, you will be asked to enter your: first name, company name, and email address.

**f.** When subscribing for Premium Woodpecker account, you will be asked to enter your first name, last name, email address, company information (name, address, registration numbers) and appropriate payment information.

**g.** When using our Service, both during the trial period as well as during the premium subscription, we will process any information you choose to provide us with, while keeping respect to your email recipients and customers (“Prospect” or “Prospects”). The Prospects’ information we process typically include names and email addresses of your customers, but will consist of any information you choose to upload to the Service. We are aware of the importance of data safety, that is why we declare that we will make no use of your prospects data. We shall not share such information with any third party and access those data only if necessary due to maintenance or support reasons.

## 2\. Why Woodpecker.co collects information about you?

**a.** Woodpecker.co collects your information to personalize your experience with the Service, Website, Blog and promotional materials we distribute via social media platforms and Google AdWords. Your information helps us more efficiently respond to your needs as a Service user and a customer, as well as a Blog reader.

**b.** Providing your information is crucial to set up an account, process payment transactions and it’s necessary for us to provide you with the Service.

**c.** Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the purpose of delivering the requested Service and improving the Service.

**d.** In the event of breaking the Terms of Service (such as sending SPAM or other prohibited content defined in the Terms of Service) we can reach the wrongdoer more efficiently.

## 3\. What does Woodpecker do with the collected information?

**a.** The information helps us constantly improve the Website, the Blog and the Service for present and future visitors and customers.

**b.** It enables us to improve our customer service, as your feedback and collected information about your activity in the Service helps us respond to your requests faster and support your needs on the way to succeeding with the Service.

**c.** Sending you periodic email updates (usually once a month) allows us to update our users once we release new functionality. The email address you provide for order processing, will be used to send you onboarding information and product updates. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails with product updates, we include “unsubscribe from this list” link at the bottom of every message. We reserve our right to send you communication and updates concerning service delivery and maintenance whenever it is necessary.

## 4\. When and What kind of information can be accessed by Woodpecker.co

**a.** We can access two types of information: personal (name, email address, company information) and general numerical information from your Account (average reply rates, open rates, the overall number of sent messages, the average number of messages per campaign, average number of words in messages, etc.).

**b.** We may access your personal information for accounting/billing purposes (such as invoicing), updating (letting you know about recent changes to our Service), in case of breaking our Terms (or suspicion of it), such as sending SPAM messages, prohibited content, or using inappropriate language (curse words, insulting, etc.).  
We may access your general numerical information from your Account for statistical purposes as well as for more efficient customer support (average reply rates, open rates, the overall number of sent messages, the average number of messages per campaign, average number of words in messages, etc.). We will only use this numerical information in order to: track the general progress of efficiency of our Service, diagnose potential problems with your email campaigns (low deliverability, low open rates, high bounce rates) and help you solve them as quickly as possible.

**c.** Our Customer Support and Customer Success teams may access your Woodpecker account upon your request in order to answer specific questions related to the Service or solving some problems you’ve reported, which have been reported to us automatically by our system or during maintenance check-ups necessary to provide the system’s fluency.

## 5\. Can you change/update your personal information?

**a.** Every user has the right to view, update and make any corrections to the content of his/her data on our system in his/her Account or by contacting support@woodpecker.co. By sharing with us your personal data you accept that we can process such information for the purpose requested by you. Access and usage of non-personal visitor information is crucial to using Website, Blog, and Service.

## 6\. How Service users can remove their personal data from Woodpecker.co?

**a.** Every user has the right to request data deletion from our system by contacting [support@woodpecker.co](mailto:support@woodpecker.co). We will try to accomplish data deletion requests nevertheless, in case of refusal due to other legal obligations we shall provide an information why such change is impossible.

## 7\. How Service users can change or remove their personal data from Woodpecker.co?

**a.** As Woodpecker user, you may change your first name, last name, company name, email address, password, and time zone at any time after logging in to their Woodpecker account. To do that, you should log into your User Account at app.woodpecker.co, choose ‘Settings’ from a drop-down menu in the top right corner and click on ‘My profile’ tab. To change the username, Woodpecker.co users should contact support team at [support@woodpecker.co](mailto:support@woodpecker.co)

**b.** Woodpecker.co users can also request deletion of their data by contacting support team at [support@woodpecker.co](mailto:support@woodpecker.co).

## 8\. How the email list subscribers can change or remove their personal data from Woodpecker.co?

**a.** As Woodpecker.co email list subscriber, you will get email messages sent by MailChimp. You can change your personal data on the subscribers list by clicking the “update subscription preferences” link in any message we have sent you using MailChimp.

**b.** You can also unsubscribe from any list by clicking the “unsubscribe from this list” link at the bottom of any message. Such a request to get unsubscribed from a list will be applied to this specific list only. If as a subscriber you wish to be removed from all the lists at once, please reply to any of the messages and write that you wish to be removed from all Woodpecker.co’s emailing lists.

## 9\. How do we protect your information?

**a.** Read more in [Safety & Security](https://woodpecker.co/safety-security/).

## 10\. GDPR compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation). In order to keep our company data processing policy coherent and applicable, we nominated Data Protection Officer: Margaret Sikora LL.M in International and European Law.  
For more details on how we comply with General Data Protection Regulation and what actions our users should take to be compliant with it as well, please go to [GDPR Compliance](https://woodpecker.co/gdpr-compliance/).

**Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our Website and Service are both dedicated to people who are at least 18 years old or older.

## 12\. Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post these changes on this page. We reserve our right to chance our Privacy Policy without prior notice to our users and visitors of our webpages.

### Contact

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at support@woodpecker.co.  
Woodpecker.co sp. z o.o.  
Krakowska 29D  
50-424 Wroclaw  
POLAND

## COOKIES POLICY NOTICE

Woodpecker.co and our third party partners, such as our advertising and analytics processors, use various technologies to collect information, such as cookies and web beacons. Therefore, we reserve our right to collect some information about you, including personal data, via browser cookies.

**1.** Do we use Cookies?

Yes, we do. Whenever you interact with our Website, Blog, and/or Service, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, “Cookie” information, and the page you requested.

“Cookies” are identifiers we transfer to your computer or mobile device that allow us to recognize your browser or mobile device and tell us how and when our Website, Blog and Service pages are visited by you. If you click on a link to a third party website directly from our Website, such third party may also transmit cookies to you. For more details and the list of Cookies we use on our Website, please check [Cookies Information](https://woodpecker.co/cookies-information/). This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.

**2.** Do we disclose any information to third parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personal information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, as long as those parties are obliged to keep this information confidential (such as payment processing or accounting services). You will find the list of those companies along with the details of what data they process, and for what purposes, in the section below.

We may also release your information when we believe the release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect our or others rights, property, or safety, as well as in the event of breaking the Terms of Service (such as sending spam and prohibited content).

However, non-personal visitor information (such as: the Device’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, the web page visited before or after you came to our website, information you search for on our website, and interactions with the Service) may be used by us for marketing, advertising, statistic purposes and to track the general progress of efficiency of our Service.

**3.** What third-party services do we use to process your information?

Depending on your engagement with our Website, Blog, and Service, we may process your information using third party processors listed below.

**  
If you are a Website visitor or a Blog visitor** , and you don’t provide your email address or other personal data to subscribe to a list or sign up for a free trial of the Service, we may only collect statistical non-personal data using Cookies. You will find more information about our use of Cookies in a separate section above.

**If you voluntarily enter your email address at the Website or the Blog** in order to subscribe for an ebook, a course, a newsletter, or another material, or to leave us a message, we may process your data using tools and software of the following data processors:

  * MailChimp ([Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/))

We use MailChimp managing lists and sending marketing email messages like newsletters, courses on specific topics, messages including links to ebooks and PDF files.

  * Facebook ([Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy))

We may process the data you provided in one of the forms at our Website or Blog using Facebook tools for customizing the content we promote and for more precise targeting of our promotional materials.

**If you sign up for a free trial of the Service** , we may process your data using tools and software of the following data processors:

  * Google ([Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/))

Upon your registration to our Service, we start processing your user id with Google Analytics, Google AdWords, Google Tag Manager. We use Google Analytics to access statistical data about our users and to discover which parts of our website and software need improvement. We promote our service and our content with Google AdWords, the data we collect about our users allows us to better target our ads as well as customize our remarketing campaigns. Google Tag Manager helps us sync all the stats we collect across all the systems we use.

  * Help Scout ([Privacy Policy](https://www.helpscout.net/company/privacy/))

Help Scout is a help desk software we use to respond to questions from our users as well as contact trial users offering some help during their free trial period. We process email addresses, first and last names as well as user id numbers via Help Scout, as those are the data necessary for sales and support communication with our users.

  * Pipedrive ([Privacy Policy](https://www.pipedrive.com/en/privacy))

Pipedrive is the CRM (customer relationship management) solution we use to keep track of our trial and premium users’ activities and our contact with them since the beginning of their trial period. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id, username, email address, first and last name and company website address with Pipedrive.

  * Mixpanel ([Privacy Policy](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/))

Mixpanel is an analytical solution that helps us understand our subscribers behavior in our service and discover the sources they came from. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id and email/username in Mixpanel.

  * InnerTrends ([Privacy Policy](https://www.innertrends.com/privacy))

InnerTrends is an analytical solution that helps us understand our subscribers behavior in our service and discover the sources they came from. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id and email/username in InnerTrends.

  * FullStory ([Privacy Policy](https://www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy/))

FullStory is an analytical solution that helps us understand our subscribers behavior in our service and assist our users with solving some of their technical problems. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id in FullStory.

**If you sign up for a premium subscription of the Service** , we may process your data using tools and software of the following data processors:

  * Braintree ([Privacy Policy](https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-pl/legal?referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.pl%2F))

We use Braintree to process payments for the Service. Braintree will process the data you enter to pay for the service your first and last name, your company name, your company address as well as your credit card details. This data processing is necessary to process the payment itself and is required for you as a premium user in order to pay for the premium subscription.

  * PayPal ([Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full))

We use PayPal to process payments for the Service. PayPal will process the data you enter to pay for the service after choosing the option to pay with your PayPal account. In such a case, they will process the same data you had provided to set up your account at PayPal. If you choose PayPal as your payment option, this data processing is necessary to process the payment itself and is required for you as a premium user in order to pay for the premium subscription.

  * Google ([Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/))

Upon your registration to our Service, we start processing your user id with Google Analytics, Google AdWords, Google Tag Manager. We use Google Analytics to access statistical data about our users and to discover which parts of our website and software need improvement. We promote our service and our content with Google AdWords, the data we collect about our users allows us to better target our ads as well as customize our remarketing campaigns. Google Tag Manager helps us sync all the stats we collect across all the systems we use.

  * Help Scout ([Privacy Policy](https://www.helpscout.net/company/privacy/))

Help Scout is a help desk software we use to respond to questions from our users as well as contact trial users offering some help during their free trial period. We process email addresses, first and last names as well as user id numbers via Help Scout, as those are the data necessary for sales and support communication with our users.

  * Pipedrive ([Privacy Policy](https://www.pipedrive.com/en/privacy))

Pipedrive is the CRM (customer relationship management) solution we use to keep track of our trial and premium users’ activities and our contact with them since the beginning of their trial period. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id, username, email address, first and last name and company website address in Pipedrive.

  * Mixpanel ([Privacy Policy](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/))

Mixpanel is an analytical solution that helps us understand our subscribers behavior in our service and discover the sources they came from. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id and email/username in Mixpanel.

  * InnerTrends ([Privacy Policy](https://www.innertrends.com/privacy))

InnerTrends is an analytical solution that helps us understand our subscribers behavior in our service and discover the sources they came from. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id and email/username in InnerTrends.

  * FullStory ([Privacy Policy](https://www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy/))

FullStory is an analytical solution that helps us understand our subscribers behavior in our service and assist our users with solving some of their technical problems. At the moment of signing up for the free trial, we start processing your user id in FullStory.
